Preliminary Guide to the Collection of Drama 131 Course Materials
Yale University Arts Library
Collection of Drama 131 Course Materials
1932-1967
DRA 24
Yale University Arts Library
1.25
(1 box)
Collection contains course readings, student papers, and technical schematics from the Drama 131 Technical Theatre course.
Yale University. Drama Library
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Collection of Drama 131 Course Materials was housed in the former Drama Library until its transfer to the Robert B. Haas Family Arts Library in 2008.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection contains course readings, student papers, and technical schematics from the Drama 131 Technical Theatre course.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically.
- Box listing
  - Switchboard Plans, 1926-1927; Yale University Theater (Box 1)
  - Experiment in the Efficiency of Canvas Glue, 1932; Schubert, Leland, 1907- (Box 1)
  - Report of Work on "Plaster Mache": Process and Uses, 1933; Schubert, Leland, 1907- (Box 1)
  - Some Test on Lumber, 1934; Aldrich, Walter N. (Box 1)
  - A Translation of "Caracteristiques Du Theatre Pigalle" and introduction to the book "Theatres-Cinemas", 1934; Koenig, Joni (Box 1)
  - Sound Effects Theory and Practice, 1934; Turner, L. Charles (Box 1)
  - A Method of Raising People on Invisible Supports, 1935; Aldrich, Walter N. (Box 1)
  - Abstract Sound Designing, 1939; Teschan, Walter E. vB. (Box 1)
  - Special Problem: "Theatre Production for Vocational Schools", 1940; Lavandero, Leopoldo S. (Box 1)
  - Report on Some Factors Affecting Recognition in the Theatre, 1940; Sarvis, David (Box 1)
  - "Get Off My Toes", 1942; Jewett, William A., Jr. (Box 1)
  - Data on Various Stage Lighting Equipments, [1948]; Povel, Louis (Box 1)
  - Ropes for the Theater, 1960; McMullan, Bruce W. (Box 1)
  - A Proposed System for fire Protection of the Proscenium Arch in the Flexible Theater, 1960; Thompson, Richard D. (Box 1)
  - Lighting Galleries for the Main Stage of the Yale University Theatre, 1962; Mancarrow, David (Box 1)
  - Propaganda Techniques and the Open Stage, 1965; Lueking, Arthur Lance (Box 1)
  - Pneumatic Staplers and Scenery Construction, 1965; Lueking, Arthur Lance (Box 1)
  - A Manual of Procedure for Purchasing and Bookkeeping at The Yale School of Drama, 1965; Ormond, Sara (Box 1)
  - Finer Glass Reinforced Plastics, 1966; McEvoy, Owen (Box 1)
  - 131 Project #3 Some Maine Hardware for the Theater, 1966; Mitchell, Dana F. (Box 1)
  - Wire Rope Nomenclature, 1966; Wechsler, Gilbert (Box 1)
  - Technical Production – Student's Papers, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
  - Efficiency in Theatrical Production, 1967; Barrow, Arthur H. (Box 1)
  - A Drama 131 Project, 1967; Barrow, Ting (Box 1)
  - A film, 1967; Ginsberg, Arthur (Box 1)
  - Drafting Convention for the Theatre, 1967; Heaton, Allen (Box 1)
  - Glossary of Rigging Terms Drama 131, 1967; Heaton, Allen (Box 1)
  - Theatrical Perspective, 1967; Jackson, Mae Laura (Box 1)
  - Holography: Three-Dimensional Projects for Theatre, 1967; Ledlow, Kent E. (Box 1)
  - Recommended Lighting Levels for the Theatre Building, 1967; Madeira, Marcia T. (Box 1)
  - Methods of Making Fog and Smoke for the Theatre, 1967; Madeira, Marcia T. (Box 1)
  - A Remotely Balanced Counterweight System, 1967; Meyer, Edwin C. (Box 1)
  - Theatrical Applications of Reproduction Equipment, 1967; Meyer, Edwin C. (Box 1)
  - Rope and Its Properties, 1967; Mitchell, Dana F. (Box 1)
  - Color Vision, 1967; Ross, Carolyn L. (Box 1)
  - Experiments with Industrial Dye and Its Use in Stage Scenery, 1967; Ross, Carolyn L. (Box 1)
  - An Overhung Swivel Loft Block for Wire Rope, 1967; Waxler, Steven (Box 1)
  - 131 Project: Video Tape and Closed Circuit T.V. for the Performing Arts, 1967; Waxler, Steven (Box 1)
  - Plan for Lifting Device for Hemp Rigging Systems, 1967; Will, G. R. (Box 1)
  - Specialized Suction, 1967; Will, Randall G. (Box 1)
  - Technical Production – Student's Paper, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Applied Three Dimensional Detail, 1967 (Box 1)
  - City Noise Group, undated; Aldrich, Walter N. (Box 1)
  - Theater Acoustics, undated; Aldrich, Walter N. (Box 1)
  - Lighting Interiors Fashion Shows, undated; Girvan, Higginson (Box 1)
  - Operations Manual for Console Control, undated; Izenour, George C.; 2 (Box 1)
  - Electronic Control for Stage Lighting, undated; Izenour, George C.; 2 (Box 1)
  - The Coming College Theatre, undated; Jones, Don (Box 1)
  - Radio Amplification for Off Stage Noises, undated; Levy, Jack F. (Box 1)
  - Lighting for the Audience, undated; McCandless, Stanley R. (Stanley Russell), 1897-; 2 (Box 1)
  - A Study of Translucencies, undated; Nelson, W. (Box 1)
  - Experiments on Breaking Strains of Lumber Sash Cord Wire, undated; Rachmil, Lewis J., 1908-1984 (Box 1)
  - Appendix III "Samples" Textiles, undated; Meyer, V. (Box 1)
  - The Imitation of Decorative Textiles For Use on the Stage, undated; Vaughan, Mary (Box 1)
  - Report on Distortion Test, undated; Winkler, Eldon A. (Box 1)
  - Sound Systems and Their Relation to the Legitimate Theater, undated; Wolff, Fred (Box 1)
  - Inventory, undated (Box 1)